Guide to the Commerce Bulletin RG.39.199
New York University Archives
Commerce Bulletin
1933-1954
New York University Archives
RG.39.199
14 Linear Feet in 44 boxes and 6 microfilm reels
This collection contains issues from the Commerce Bulletin dating from 1933 to 1954. This newspaper documented student life at NYU's School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance (known today as the Stern School of Business). The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. Issues are in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Box 40 includes the Collegiate Digest, which was a periodical of national college news and photography published by the Associated Collegiate Press.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must consult microfilm copies due to the fragility of the original newspapers.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Newspapers are arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues from the Commerce Bulletin dating from 1933 to 1954. This newspaper documented student life at NYU's School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance (known today as the Stern School of Business). The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. Issues are in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Box 40 includes the Collegiate Digest, which was a periodical of national college news and photography published by the Associated Collegiate Press.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Historical Note
The New York University undergraduate School of Commerce, Accounts and Finance was established in 1900 to provide professional training for students pursuing a career in business. The school was presided over by Charles Waldo Haskins, the school's founding dean.
In 1972, the School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance was renamed the College of Business and Public Administration. In 1988, alumnus Leonard N. Stern gave the school a generous donation, allowing the school to consolidate its graduate and undergraduate facilities at NYU's Washington Square campus. The school was renamed the Leonard N. Stern School of Business.
Today, NYU Stern is one of the nation's premier management education schools and research centers with a broad portfolio of academic programs at the graduate and undergraduate levels.
Sources:
1. NYU Stern, "History", accessed November 19, 2018, available online at http://www.stern.nyu.edu/experience-stern/about/history
2. NYU Stern, "Timeline", accessed November 19, 2018, available online at http://www.stern.nyu.edu/experience-stern/about/history/timeline
Business schools; College student newspapers and periodicals.; Student activities.
- Microfilm copies
  - Reel 5039, February 1933 - May 1936 (Box Microfilm 6)
  - Reel 5040, September 1936 - May 1940 (Box Microfilm 6)
  - Reel 5041, September 1940 - May 1944 (Box Microfilm 6)
  - Reel 5042, October 1944 - May 1949 (Box Microfilm 6)
  - Reel 5043, September 1949 - May 1953 (Box Microfilm 6)
  - Reel 5044, September 1953 - May 1954 (Box Microfilm 6)
- Bound print copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Commerce Bulletin (2 copies), February 1933 - May 1933 (Box 6, Box Shared University Archives 080)
  - Commerce Bulletin, October 1933 - May 1934 (2 copies) (Box 1)
  - Commerce Bulletin, October 1934 - May 1935 (3 copies) (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1935 - May 1936 (4 copies) (Box 3, Box 4)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1936 - May 1937 (3 copies) (Box 5, Box 6)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1937 - May 1938 (Box 7)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1938 - May 1939 (4 copies) (Box 7, Box 8)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1939- May 1940 (Box 9)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1940 - May 1941 (2 copies) (Box 10)
  - Commerce Bulletin, December 1940 - May 1941 (2 copies) (Box 11)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1941 - May 1942 (2 copies) (Box 12)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1942 - May 1943 (4 copies) (Box 13, Box 14)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1943 - May 1944 (4 copies) (Box 15, Box 16)
  - Commerce Bulletin, October 1944 - May 1945 (8 copies) (Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1945 - May 1946 (Box 21)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1946 - May 1947 (3 copies) (Box 21, Box 22)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1947 - May 1948 (Box 27)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1948 - May 1949 (6 copies) (Box 23, Box 24, Box 25)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1949 - May 1950 (7 copies) (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1950 - May 1951 (6 copies) (Box 30, Box 31, Box 32)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1951 - May 1952 (8 copies) (Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1952 - May 1953 (2 copies) (Box 36, Box 37)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1953 - May 1954 (2 copies) (Box 38)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1954 - May 1955 (2 copies) (Box 39)
- Print copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Commerce Bulletin, October 1933 - February 1944 (Box 40)
  - Commerce Bulletin, February 1933 - November 1949 (Box 41)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1939 - May 1940, October 1944 - March 1947 (Box 42)
  - Commerce Bulletin Golden Anniversary Edition, February 1950 (Box 40)
  - Commerce Bulletin, September 1953 - May 1954 (Box 43)